<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Preservation Notes</title>
    <link>http://decirella.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Preservation Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 11:31:47 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://decirella.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mkisofs</title>
      <link>http://decirella.github.io/posts/mkisofs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 11:31:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://decirella.github.io/posts/mkisofs/</guid>
      <description>A recent project that involved working with a Windows 98 installation running in emulation (QEMU) needed an update installed from a .exe. Needing to get the .exe from my desktop into the Windows 98 environment posed a problem to solve. There are likely many solutions to this problem, the one I found, with the quickest resolution was to create a .iso formatted disk image (iso9660) to mount as a cdrom in the emulated environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diagrams</title>
      <link>http://decirella.github.io/posts/diagrams/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 09:09:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://decirella.github.io/posts/diagrams/</guid>
      <description>Many times throughout the life of a project I find the need to create some visual component to go along with planning or communicating about some component of a system or technology. After coming to this conclusion, the next step is so often a question of what tool to use for the task! I have used several solutions that broadly fall into two categories: text-based and graphics-based.
On the text-based side I&amp;rsquo;ve been really enjoying using plantuml for creating various types of diagrams specified in text converted to an image.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>init_post</title>
      <link>http://decirella.github.io/posts/init_post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 10:14:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://decirella.github.io/posts/init_post/</guid>
      <description>Welcome! The plan for this space is to host semi-public, informal notes documenting various digital preservation, software development, and technology-related topics.</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
